Anh Hoang Nguyen's Resume

Website: https://aaanh.ca

Mail: iam@hoanganh.dev

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/aaanh

GitHub: https://github.com/aaanh

Introduction

I actively work on modern web applications, APIs, frameworks and machine learning research projects in natural language processing (NLP) and computer vision (CV).

In addition in my free time, I build scalable distributed compute clusters with monitoring using hypervisor and container technologies, most notably my homelab.

Professional Experience

Software Developer — Internship (1/2023 — 5/2023)

Nuance Communications + Microsoft, Montréal, QC.

Healthcare AI solutions & services. Deep learning solutions in multiple industries.

- Core Technology R&D
- Develop backend API and microservices.

Software Developer in SCMT/DevOps — Internship (5/2022 — 9/2022)

Genetec Inc., Saint-Laurent, QC.

Hardware, software, and service provider in physical security, access control, and federated cloud-based security center.

- Completed 2 projects involving internal service migrations to on-premise Docker container cluster.
- Developed automated scripts for bulk requests with Azure DevOps API endpoints.
- Created and maintained software build and release pipelines for multiple target platforms: web app, native Windows, native Linux.
- Maintained and troubleshooted infrastructure incidents: Identity and Access Management, networking, OS performance.

Research Assistant — Casual (1/2021 — now)

SAC Research Group, Concordia University.

Cloud architecture, system architecture, AI and ML applications research group

• My current project is to evaluate MLaaS platforms and develop an assessment framework.

 Assist in researching practical applications of machine learning and deep learning models with current focus on explainable AI (XAI).

- Replicate experiments to verify claims arising during the research of a topic.
- Gather information from research literatures and extract meaningful points to aid in the research progress of the group.
- Previously, I contributed by running and reporting NLP models for classification on non-Latin datasets, more specifically XLNet and bert.
- Maintain and develop the group's website.

Full-Stack Developer — Contract (1/2021 — now)

Inertial Sensing Lab, Montreal, QC.

Physics research lab specializes on inertial and mechanical operations using accelerometer sensors.

- Build and maintain the project website.
- The website is a hub for both internal and public communications, functioning as a knowledge base, blog, archive, and file repository.
- Architect and implement the tech stacks and the UI/UX design to the web hosting, networking, security, and identity & access management.

IT Technician L2 — Part-time (3/2021 — now)

Academic IT Services, Concordia University.

I.T. organization specialized in developing and servicing information systems for the Engineering and Computer Science school.

- Offer frontline support to the customers in terms of utilizing the IT infrastructures, services, and resources at Concordia.
- Investigate complicate issues regarding physical systems, networking, internal accounts, and access controls to resolve or to escalate to SysAdmins and NetAdmins.
- Suggest insightful improvements for service desk work processes and cross-team communications.
- Regularly check the teaching lab peripherals (i.e., computers, monitors, projectors), and troubleshoot the found issues.
- Service the walk-in customer or in labs, and answering the phone call.
- Utilize the ticketing system to offer efficient IT support.
- Work in conjunction with full-time staff to ensure the functionality of computer labs.
- Perform inventory for new purchases (computers and equipment) by the engineering faculty.
- Undertake other job-related missions assigned by the manager of User Services.

IT Support Specialist — Internship (8/2021 — 12/2021)

Genetec Inc., Saint-Laurent, QC.

- Provide technical assistance and troubleshooting for users.
- Perform infra and team workflow improvement tasks.
- Test new hardware and software compatibility in the environment.
- Manage hybrid AD and Endpoint, account credentials and permission groups.
- Deploy IT assets: hardware and software.

- Utilize PowerShell and bash scripting.
- Manage cloud VMs and KVM/Hyper-V.
- Extensive use of Jira ticketing system and contribute to internal wiki.
- Handle IT phone calls.
- Maintain asset inventory and specifications. Troubleshoot computer hardware issues.
- Manage access request according to InfoSec policies.
- Work usually encompasses OSI layers 5 to 7.

Notable Projects

Portfolio Site – https://aaanh.ca

- Built with Nextjs framework for Reactjs.
- Custom-styled and themed with TailwindCSS.
- Implemented with API endpoints for Spotify play status.

Script Convenience Store - https://aaanh.app

- A repository for copy-pasting arcane commands on Linux, Windows, and macOS in case someone forgets.
- Built with Book.md framework running on Rust.
- CI/CD with Github Actions.
- Deployed on Vercel.

Personal Photo Reels - https://photos.aaanh.ca

- My straightforward photo reel of urban and natural landscapes
- Built with Nextjs, Tailwind CSS. Front-end and API hosted on Vercel. Asset storage and transformation API on Cloudinary. Cloudflare for caching, edge CDN, and DNS.

NAG-DevOps/speed-hpc - https://github.com/NAG-DevOps/speed-hpc

- · Concordia University's HPC cluster.
- Develop Latex to HTML build pipeline for the documentation.
- Create battery-included devcontainer environment for authoring LaTeX.
- Create GitHub Actions pipeline for deploying the HTML docs.

Development Blog – https://ml.aaanh.com

- A blog built with Nextjs and Tailwind CSS (hosted on Netlify with Github Actions CI) where I write about new techs, tools, and knowledge I come across through my everyday life.
- Routed and SSL'd through Cloudflare.

Personal URL Shortener - https://s.aaanh.ca

• A simple URL shortener in Nextjs.

Data Object Parse and Meaningful Graph Traversal – https://github.com/aaanh/meaningful-graph-traversal.git

- Final project for 2nd level OOP course.
- Clean the Panama Papers .csv dataset using Python notebook and pandas.
- Parse the cleaned dataset using C++ into graphs and nodes.
- Output connections between nodes using BFS traversal.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Engineering with Co-op (2020 — 2024)

Concordia University, Montréal, QC.

DEC in Pure and Applied Sciences (2017 — 2020)

John Abbott College, Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, QC.

Skills

- Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Java.
- Specializations: Full-stack web development, IAM, cloud-sec, DevSecOps/SRE, containerization
- Environments: Linux, macOS, Windows and respective CLI's.
- Tools: Agile process, git, bash/zsh, PowerShell, vim, vscode, conda, OSINT framework.
- Cloud Services: Google Cloud Platform (functions, firebase, gke, compute-engine, Vertex), AWS (SageMaker, EC2), Azure (AAD, ADO)
- Infra Tools: Ansible, Terraform, k8s, qemu, VMWare Sphere, Hyper-V
- Natural languages: vi-vn (native), en-us/ca/uk (bilingual), fr-ca (B1), ja-jp (N5), de-de (casual).
- Personal: Professional manner, responsible, great analytical mindset, willing to learn, team player, empathetic.

Awards

• FRQNT Stipend Recipient, October 2020, for work in Inertial Sensing Lab under Prof. Larnder.

Other Interests

- Music, cultural exchange, travelling.
- Messing around with Awesome Selfhosted.
- Gaming.